[
  {
    "question": "At what depth do dolphins usually feed?",
    "answer": "30 meters"
  },
  {
    "question": "Do jawless vertebrates have a backbone?",
    "answer": "No"
  },
  {
    "question": "For what purpose do echinoderms expel their internal organs when in extreme danger?",
    "answer": "Defense"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do cephalopods move?",
    "answer": "Jet propulsion"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do echinoderms reproduce?",
    "answer": "Sexually"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do fish navigate in the dark?",
    "answer": "Lateral line"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do gastropods protect themselves from predators?",
    "answer": "Shell"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do lancelets reproduce?",
    "answer": "Spawning"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do octopuses defend themselves?",
    "answer": "ink"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do sea cucumbers clean their insides when threatened?",
    "answer": "Eject their organs"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do sea cucumbers feed?",
    "answer": "Filtering water"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do spiders digest their food?",
    "answer": "externally"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do starfish maintain balance?",
    "answer": "With their tube feet"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does a hagfish defend itself from predators?",
    "answer": "Mucopolysaccharides"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does an anaconda obtain its food?",
    "answer": "hunting"
  },
  {
    "question": "How does the southern right whale store fat?",
    "answer": "Blubber"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is a mini-greenhouse used?",
    "answer": "Growing seedlings"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long do carrot seeds remain viable?",
    "answer": "2-3 years"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long do macaques live?",
    "answer": "35 years"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long do most ants live?",
    "answer": "Several years"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long does digestion take in a lancelet?",
    "answer": "Several hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long does whale migration last?",
    "answer": "Several months"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many extinct species of whales are known?",
    "answer": "More than 20"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many eyes do flies have?",
    "answer": "5"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many fins does a lamprey have?",
    "answer": "None"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many gill openings does a lamprey have?",
    "answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many gill slits do jawless fish have?",
    "answer": "Up to 100"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many gold medals does Michael Phelps have?",
    "answer": "23"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many liters of blood are in the heart of a blue whale?",
    "answer": "600"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many liters of water does a blue whale filter at once?",
    "answer": "10000 liters"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many nature reserves are there in Russia?",
    "answer": "103"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many pairs of gills do jawless fish have?",
    "answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many pairs of gills does a lancelet have?",
    "answer": "6-7 pairs"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many phases are there in the game 'Pandemic'?",
    "answer": "5"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many radial canals does a starfish have?",
    "answer": "Five"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many segments does a caterpillar have in its body?",
    "answer": "13"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of dolphins are there?",
    "answer": "32"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of galago are there?",
    "answer": "20"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of geckos are there?",
    "answer": "1600+"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of gibbons are there?",
    "answer": "Sixteen"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of lancelets are there?",
    "answer": "More than 30"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of lemurs are there?",
    "answer": "About 100"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of lizards exist in the world?",
    "answer": "6000"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of mollusks are there?",
    "answer": "More than 100,000"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of monitor lizards are there?",
    "answer": "80"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of rays are there?",
    "answer": "More than 500"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of sharks are there?",
    "answer": "About 520"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of snakes exist in the world?",
    "answer": "more than 3000"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many species of whales are there?",
    "answer": "About 90"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many tentacles does an argopect have?",
    "answer": "Ten"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many types of gills do sharks have?",
    "answer": "Two"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many types of tissues do lancelets have?",
    "answer": "Four"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many years does a beluga whale live?",
    "answer": "60"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many years does the probation period last after being released from prison?",
    "answer": "2"
  },
  {
    "question": "How much does a blue whale weigh on average?",
    "answer": "150 tons"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to control overwatering?",
    "answer": "Moisture sensor"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to deal with wireworms?",
    "answer": "Using traps"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to optimize water usage in an irrigation system?",
    "answer": "Install timers"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what type of water do hagfish lay their eggs?",
    "answer": "Saltwater"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year was the game Watch Dogs: Legion released?",
    "answer": "Survival Craft"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which century were lancelets first described?",
    "answer": "19th century"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which century were the first fossils of jawed vertebrates discovered?",
    "answer": "19th century"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which game are there transportation cards?",
    "answer": "Ticket to Ride"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which game can you become the captain of a spaceship?",
    "answer": "FTL: Faster Than Light"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which game can you develop a mountain base?",
    "answer": "Frostpunk"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which game do you explore dungeons and roll dice for battles?",
    "answer": "DungeonQuest"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which game do you need to grow plants to defend against zombies?",
    "answer": "Plants vs Zombies"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which game does the hero fight against robots?",
    "answer": "Blasphemous"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which game is Alduin featured?",
    "answer": "Skyrim"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which game is the FaZe Clan team popular?",
    "answer": "Call of Duty"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which game is the location Lileynoe Pole featured?",
    "answer": "Xenoblade Chronicles"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which nature reserve can orange cuckoos be found?",
    "answer": "Barguzinsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which nature reserve can you find reed cats?",
    "answer": "Dagestan Reserve"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which nature reserve can you see the rare white stork?",
    "answer": "Rostovsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which nature reserve do Arctic foxes live?",
    "answer": "Verkhne-Tazovsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which nature reserve do Caucasian storks live?",
    "answer": "Shaumyan"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which nature reserve do leopards live near the Amur River?",
    "answer": "Lazovsky Nature Reserve"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which nature reserve do red pandas live?",
    "answer": "Sikhote-Alin"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which nature reserve do snow leopards live?",
    "answer": "Sailugemsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which nature reserve does the Eastern spiny-tailed lizard live?",
    "answer": "Astrakhan"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which nature reserve does the rare sea comb live?",
    "answer": "Far Eastern Marine Reserve"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which ocean do giant squids live?",
    "answer": "Atlantic"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which ocean do hagfish live?",
    "answer": "Pacific"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which part of the world do pandas live, feeding on bamboo?",
    "answer": "Asia"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which period did the first jawed vertebrates appear?",
    "answer": "Silurian"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which region do tsetse flies live?",
    "answer": "Africa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the magical art of elven mages in the game Dragon Age.",
    "answer": "Arcanum"
  },
  {
    "question": "The most venomous mammal?",
    "answer": "Platypus"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which class do echinoderms with long tentacles belong?",
    "answer": "Holothuroidea"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which family do chimpanzees belong?",
    "answer": "Hominidae"
  },
  {
    "question": "What animal is dominant in the tundra?",
    "answer": "Musk ox"
  },
  {
    "question": "What animals inhabit the Caucasian Reserve?",
    "answer": "Caucasian bison"
  },
  {
    "question": "What animals inhabit the Darwin Reserve?",
    "answer": "Sea otters"
  },
  {
    "question": "What animals inhabit the Yamal Nature Reserve?",
    "answer": "Musk oxen"
  },
  {
    "question": "What animals live in the desert?",
    "answer": "Camel"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Japanese gardens decorated with?",
    "answer": "Rocks and sand"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are arthropods with jaws called?",
    "answer": "Mandibulates"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are brittle stars?",
    "answer": "A type of echinoderms"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are compost worms used for?",
    "answer": "To decompose materials"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are enclosing structures used for?",
    "answer": "Zoning"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are games with multiple participants in a single session called?",
    "answer": "Session games"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are intensive tests for games called?",
    "answer": "Stress tests"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are nocturnal primates called?",
    "answer": "Aye-Aye"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are organisms that glow in the dark called?",
    "answer": "Bioluminescent"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are pedicellariae in sea urchins?",
    "answer": "Small pincers"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are scientists who study insects called?",
    "answer": "entomologists"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the ancient ancestors of the lancelet called?",
    "answer": "Pikaia"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the combs protruding from the mantle edge of a mollusk called?",
    "answer": "Cirri"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the dorsal and ventral sides of lancelets covered with?",
    "answer": "buds"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the early stages of development in cephalochordates called?",
    "answer": "Larvae"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the eyes of most insects called?",
    "answer": "Compound"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the fangs of spiders called?",
    "answer": "Chelicerae"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the fish called that live in the anode?",
    "answer": "Anodores"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the main characteristics of primates?",
    "answer": "Large brain"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the protective shields of crayfish called?",
    "answer": "Carapaces"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the ring-shaped muscles in lancelets called?",
    "answer": "myomeres"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the smallest antelopes called?",
    "answer": "Dik-diks"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the specialized respiratory organs in spiders called?",
    "answer": "Book lungs"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the well-adapted for swimming jawed fish called?",
    "answer": "Sharks"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are warm substrates used for?",
    "answer": "Soil warming"
  },
  {
    "question": "What aspect of training helps biathletes manage adrenaline during shooting?",
    "answer": "Meditation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What cards are used for healing in the original games?",
    "answer": "Potion cards"
  },
  {
    "question": "What color is most commonly predominant in deep-sea fish?",
    "answer": "Dark"
  },
  {
    "question": "What creature is known as the 'seahorse'?",
    "answer": "seahorse"
  },
  {
    "question": "What determines the hunting difficulty for sharks?",
    "answer": "Teeth"
  },
  {
    "question": "What distinguishes baboons?",
    "answer": "They inhabit savannas"
  },
  {
    "question": "What distinguishes male and female octopuses?",
    "answer": "Reproductive organs"
  },
  {
    "question": "What distinguishes sea urchins from starfish?",
    "answer": "Body shape"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do ants use for communication?",
    "answer": "Pheromones"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do goats like to eat?",
    "answer": "Leaves"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do lampreys eat?",
    "answer": "Blood of fish"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do mollusks use siphons for?",
    "answer": "Filtering food"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do spiders eat?",
    "answer": "Insects"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do these beetles lack?",
    "answer": "Wings"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does a compost thermometer measure?",
    "answer": "Temperature of compost"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does a pH meter measure?",
    "answer": "Soil acidity"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does a sea cucumber release when threatened?",
    "answer": "Internal organs"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does a shell secrete?",
    "answer": "Nacre"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does lateral symmetry mean in echinoderms?",
    "answer": "Bilateral symmetry"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the Great Arctic Reserve protect?",
    "answer": "Arctic nature"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the notochord in lancelets represent?",
    "answer": "Rigid rod"
  },
  {
    "question": "What element links the hero and their ability in Hearthstone?",
    "answer": "Hero card"
  },
  {
    "question": "What environment is created to attract beneficial insects?",
    "answer": "Biotopes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What equipment is used to remove old turf?",
    "answer": "Aerator"
  },
  {
    "question": "What feeding method do most brittle stars use?",
    "answer": "Detritivory"
  },
  {
    "question": "What fish inhabits the Nile River?",
    "answer": "Nile perch"
  },
  {
    "question": "What fish is called the sea devil?",
    "answer": "sea devil"
  },
  {
    "question": "What fish is most commonly caught in sport fishing?",
    "answer": "Salmon"
  },
  {
    "question": "What fish lives in caves and is blind?",
    "answer": "Cavefish"
  },
  {
    "question": "What flowers are planted in the fall?",
    "answer": "Tulips"
  },
  {
    "question": "What function do ancient gill slits serve in jawless vertebrates?",
    "answer": "Respiratory"
  },
  {
    "question": "What function do pedicellariae serve in echinoderms?",
    "answer": "Protection"
  },
  {
    "question": "What function do the baleen plates serve in whales?",
    "answer": "Filtering food"
  },
  {
    "question": "What function does geotropism serve in lancelets?",
    "answer": "Orientation in water"
  },
  {
    "question": "What function does the dental plate serve in hagfish?",
    "answer": "food capture"
  },
  {
    "question": "What function does the mantle serve in mollusks?",
    "answer": "Protection of the body"
  },
  {
    "question": "What function does the respiratory system perform?",
    "answer": "Beaver"
  },
  {
    "question": "What function does the tail serve in primates?",
    "answer": "Balance"
  },
  {
    "question": "What function does the tongue serve in snakes?",
    "answer": "Sensing smells"
  },
  {
    "question": "What game engine is used in The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim?",
    "answer": "Yakuza"
  },
  {
    "question": "What garden element often serves as a focal point?",
    "answer": "Fountain"
  },
  {
    "question": "What genre of VR games is suitable for fitness?",
    "answer": "Roguelike"
  },
  {
    "question": "What genre of game is considered a team strategy?",
    "answer": "MOBA"
  },
  {
    "question": "What helps to control watering remotely?",
    "answer": "Wi-Fi controller"
  },
  {
    "question": "What helps to save water in drip irrigation?",
    "answer": "Controller"
  },
  {
    "question": "What irrigation system is used for slow soil moisture?",
    "answer": "Capillary irrigation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a madreporite?",
    "answer": "Entrance to the ambulacral system"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a pedicellaria?",
    "answer": "Pincers"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a trepang?",
    "answer": "Sea cucumber"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a unique feature of the humpback whale's migration?",
    "answer": "Songs"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is added to compost to improve its structure?",
    "answer": "Sawdust"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an API?",
    "answer": "Application Interface"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an Argopecten?",
    "answer": "Mollusk"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an anemone?",
    "answer": "sea flower"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an effective method for mosquito control?",
    "answer": "Biological methods"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is characteristic of jawed fish?",
    "answer": "Regeneration of teeth"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is hydroponics?",
    "answer": "Soilless cultivation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is ichthyology?",
    "answer": "The science of fish"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is needed to grow a bonsai?",
    "answer": "Patience"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is needed to stabilize the pH of compost?",
    "answer": "Lime"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is needed to warm the soil in a greenhouse?",
    "answer": "Heaters"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is permaculture?",
    "answer": "Sustainable agriculture"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is special about geckos' eyes?",
    "answer": "No eyelids"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the ability called that characters can use in the game The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim?",
    "answer": "Dragonborn"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the action called when rugby players make contact in a contest for the ball on the ground?",
    "answer": "Ruck"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the ambulacral system?",
    "answer": "Hydraulic organ"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the attack value of Tarnuhar in the game Gwent?",
    "answer": "10"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the average number of eggs laid by a cockroach at one time?",
    "answer": "16"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the average number of teeth a shark has?",
    "answer": "Up to 3000"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the average speed of a shark?",
    "answer": "40 km/h"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the best fertilizer to use for strawberries?",
    "answer": "Compost"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the body length of a lamprey?",
    "answer": "Astrakhan Nature Reserve"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the brain size of a chimpanzee?",
    "answer": "400 grams"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the class to which lampreys and hagfish belong called?",
    "answer": "Cyclostomes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct name for a hose with small holes?",
    "answer": "Soaker"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the dorsal fin of a humpback whale called?",
    "answer": "Hump"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the duration of humpback whale migration?",
    "answer": "6 months"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the evolutionary position of jawless vertebrates in the history of vertebrates?",
    "answer": "The most ancient"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the function of a whale's dorsal fin?",
    "answer": "Stabilization"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the goal of organic farming?",
    "answer": "Sustainable development"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the largest living mollusk?",
    "answer": "Giant squid"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the largest reptile in the world?",
    "answer": "Saltwater crocodile"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the largest shark in the world?",
    "answer": "Whale shark"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the leg span of the largest crab in the world?",
    "answer": "3.8 meters"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the life cycle of a lamprey?",
    "answer": "Complete cycle"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the life cycle of insects called?",
    "answer": "Metamorphosis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main cause of sea urchin mortality?",
    "answer": "Predators"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main difference between lampreys and fish?",
    "answer": "absence of jaws"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main function of the ambulacral system?",
    "answer": "Locomotion"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main objective in the game Monument Valley?",
    "answer": "Solving puzzles"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main purpose of the Oksky Nature Reserve?",
    "answer": "Breeding of European bison"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum depth at which cephalopods can live?",
    "answer": "3000 meters"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum length a cobra can reach?",
    "answer": "5.5 meters"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum length an anaconda can reach?",
    "answer": "12 meters"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum length of a baleen whale's baleen?",
    "answer": "4 meters"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum shell length of a turtle?",
    "answer": "up to 200 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the method of growing vegetables without using soil called?",
    "answer": "Hydroponics"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the mode called in Assassin's Creed IV where you can control a ship?",
    "answer": "Naval Battles"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the molting process in arthropods called?",
    "answer": "Ecdysis"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the most poisonous fish?",
    "answer": "Stonefish"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the most prestigious Hearthstone tournament?",
    "answer": "World Championship"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of a garden corner designed for relaxation and meditation?",
    "answer": "Harmony"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of a small nomadic animal with a long nose?",
    "answer": "Anteater"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of a toothed whale?",
    "answer": "Odontocete"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the VR game where players can explore the world using a portal gun?",
    "answer": "Portal Stories: VR"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the ancient Chinese game with black and white stones?",
    "answer": "Go"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the annual Tekken 7 tournament?",
    "answer": "Tekken World Tour"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the dental apparatus in rays?",
    "answer": "Plates"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the family of predatory fish?",
    "answer": "Pike"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the fictional mirror in the game Mirror's Edge?",
    "answer": "Catalyst"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the fish that can generate electricity?",
    "answer": "Electric eel"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the fish with a long snout?",
    "answer": "Seahorse"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the game about managing a city-state in the ancient world?",
    "answer": "Caesar"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the game where you need to line up rows of identical tiles?",
    "answer": "Bejeweled"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the mollusk with a shell as transparent as glass?",
    "answer": "Glass octopus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the nocturnal primate with big eyes?",
    "answer": "Aye-aye"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the open part of the ocean where whales live?",
    "answer": "Pelagic zone"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the open-world game with resource gathering in survival mode?",
    "answer": "Rust"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the opening after 1.e4 c6?",
    "answer": "Caro-Kann Defense"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the organ that emits electrical signals in electric fish?",
    "answer": "Electric organ"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the popular game mode with 100-card decks?",
    "answer": "Commander"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the potent mollusk toxin?",
    "answer": "Tetrodotoxin"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the railway simulator by Dovetail Games?",
    "answer": "Train Simulator"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the small South American monkey with a ringed tail?",
    "answer": "marmoset"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the small town in the game Oxenfree?",
    "answer": "Camena"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the smallest primate?",
    "answer": "Mouse lemur"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the soil cultivation tool invented by Fokin?",
    "answer": "Flat-cutter"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the space battle simulation game?",
    "answer": "Ingress"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the strategy game that focuses primarily on submarine management?",
    "answer": "Silent Hunter"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the notochord of a lancelet made of?",
    "answer": "Cartilage"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the number of gill openings in hagfish?",
    "answer": "6-14"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the optimal moisture level for composting?",
    "answer": "40-60%"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the optimal temperature for Chinese cabbage germination?",
    "answer": "15-20°C"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the part of a sea urchin called that releases toxins?",
    "answer": "Poison gland"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the place called where saltwater and freshwater meet?",
    "answer": "Estuary"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary food that lampreys eat?",
    "answer": "Small fish"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary function of the water vascular system in echinoderms?",
    "answer": "Hydrostatic pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process called when a fish opens and closes its gills?",
    "answer": "Gill breathing"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of bringing a game to a release-ready state called?",
    "answer": "Fixing"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of creating and synchronizing the movements of characters and objects called?",
    "answer": "Animation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of digestion in starfish called?",
    "answer": "External"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of evolution of fish into land animals called?",
    "answer": "Tetrapodization"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of supplying water underground called?",
    "answer": "Subsurface irrigation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the process of trimming shrubs into geometric shapes called?",
    "answer": "Topiary"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the property of a snake's special scales?",
    "answer": "Protection"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of drainage in a greenhouse?",
    "answer": "Removal of water"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the role of squids in the ecosystem?",
    "answer": "Predators and prey"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the science of fish called?",
    "answer": "Ichthyology"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the science of growing flowers called?",
    "answer": "Floriculture"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the science that studies reptiles called?",
    "answer": "Herpetology"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the smallest insect in the world?",
    "answer": "Trichogramma wasp"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the stage of development called when an insect turns into a pupa?",
    "answer": "Pupa"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the swimming speed of a fin whale?",
    "answer": "up to 50 km/h"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the tool called for creating narrow grooves?",
    "answer": "Ploskorez"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the tool called for working with stone?",
    "answer": "Pickaxe"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the vertical mast on the neutral line called?",
    "answer": "Antenna"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the weight of an orangutan?",
    "answer": "90 kg"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the world in The Elder Scrolls called?",
    "answer": "Nirn"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is unique about dragonfly eyes?",
    "answer": "Compound eyes"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is used to lift large stones?",
    "answer": "Winch"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is used to loosen the soil after rain?",
    "answer": "Cultivator"
  },
  {
    "question": "What length can a blue whale reach?",
    "answer": "30 meters"
  },
  {
    "question": "What length can a reticulated python reach?",
    "answer": "up to 10 meters"
  },
  {
    "question": "What level of moisture is important for compost?",
    "answer": "Moderate"
  },
  {
    "question": "What mechanic allows you to draw additional cards in Magic: The Gathering?",
    "answer": "Draw"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method helps control pests naturally?",
    "answer": "Crop rotation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method improves soil?",
    "answer": "Green manure"
  },
  {
    "question": "What methods contribute to pest biocontrol?",
    "answer": "Polyculture"
  },
  {
    "question": "What methods of controlling nematodes are popular?",
    "answer": "Biological"
  },
  {
    "question": "What natural enemy helps against aphids?",
    "answer": "Ladybugs"
  },
  {
    "question": "What natural method helps protect cabbage from pests?",
    "answer": "Mulching"
  },
  {
    "question": "What natural remedy is effective against spider mites?",
    "answer": "Phytoseiulus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What organ does a shark use to detect prey?",
    "answer": "Ampullae of Lorenzini"
  },
  {
    "question": "What organisms does an anteater prefer to eat?",
    "answer": "Termites"
  },
  {
    "question": "What parameter is important to consider when watering plants?",
    "answer": "Soil moisture"
  },
  {
    "question": "What pest control method is environmentally friendly?",
    "answer": "Garlic infusion"
  },
  {
    "question": "What plant do manatees eat?",
    "answer": "Seaweed"
  },
  {
    "question": "What plants are called ground cover plants?",
    "answer": "Periwinkle"
  },
  {
    "question": "What prevents overheating in a greenhouse?",
    "answer": "ventilation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What rare predators inhabit the Caucasian Reserve?",
    "answer": "Leopards"
  },
  {
    "question": "What recovery method is considered the most effective after workouts?",
    "answer": "Contrast shower"
  },
  {
    "question": "What reptile inhabits the Galapagos Islands?",
    "answer": "Galapagos tortoise"
  },
  {
    "question": "What resource is needed to change characters?",
    "answer": "Growth Cards"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role do pedipalps serve in spiders?",
    "answer": "Sensation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What role do primates often play in the ecosystem?",
    "answer": "Seed dispersal"
  },
  {
    "question": "What running technique optimizes energy in a marathon?",
    "answer": "Economical style"
  },
  {
    "question": "What sea creature inhabits the deepest parts of the ocean?",
    "answer": "Deep-sea fish"
  },
  {
    "question": "What separates the head from the thorax in insects?",
    "answer": "Neck"
  },
  {
    "question": "What shape are the eyes of dragonflies?",
    "answer": "Compound"
  },
  {
    "question": "What should be considered when choosing polycarbonate for a greenhouse?",
    "answer": "thickness and UV protection"
  },
  {
    "question": "What should you do if aphids appear on plants?",
    "answer": "Treat with insecticide"
  },
  {
    "question": "What size can lampreys reach?",
    "answer": "Up to 100 cm"
  },
  {
    "question": "What species of monitor lizard is native to Australia?",
    "answer": "Mertens' water monitor"
  },
  {
    "question": "What speed can the fastest whales reach?",
    "answer": "40 km/h"
  },
  {
    "question": "What strategic technique involves sacrificing material for positional advantage?",
    "answer": "Strategic gambit"
  },
  {
    "question": "What strategy allows you to defend against attacks with strong spin?",
    "answer": "Counter-attacking tactic"
  },
  {
    "question": "What structure do ticks have?",
    "answer": "Chelicerae"
  },
  {
    "question": "What systems are useful to use in a greenhouse?",
    "answer": "Misting"
  },
  {
    "question": "What technology in skis allows for effective handling of hard slopes?",
    "answer": "Titanal"
  },
  {
    "question": "What temperature can biomass withstand?",
    "answer": "From 50 to 70°C"
  },
  {
    "question": "What temperature is suitable for growing citrus fruits?",
    "answer": "+15 +25 °C"
  },
  {
    "question": "What thickness of glass is often used for greenhouses?",
    "answer": "4 mm"
  },
  {
    "question": "What tool is used for mulching?",
    "answer": "Mulcher"
  },
  {
    "question": "What tool is used to create new cards in Hearthstone?",
    "answer": "The Forge"
  },
  {
    "question": "What training technique is used to improve reaction to various conditions on the track?",
    "answer": "Mental preparation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of fertilizer is used for citrus plants?",
    "answer": "nitrogen-phosphorus"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of fertilizers are best suited for flowers?",
    "answer": "Organic"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of fish is androgynous?",
    "answer": "Eel"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of game is 'Carcassonne'?",
    "answer": "Strategy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of grass cover is used for green manure?",
    "answer": "Green manure"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of greenhouse is best suited for obtaining an early harvest?",
    "answer": "Tunnel"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of greenhouse is best suited for year-round use?",
    "answer": "Permanent"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of lighting is not recommended for use in a greenhouse?",
    "answer": "Sunlight"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of mosquito transmits the Zika virus?",
    "answer": "Aedes aegypti"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of nervous system does a lamprey have?",
    "answer": "Central"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of plants grow well in sandy soil?",
    "answer": "Succulents"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of plants is used for green roofs?",
    "answer": "Succulents"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of skeleton do jawed fish have?",
    "answer": "Bony"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of skeleton do jawed vertebrates have?",
    "answer": "Cartilaginous"
  },
  {
    "question": "What unique ability does the 'Worgen' class have in World of Warcraft?",
    "answer": "Transformation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What unique feature do lancelets have?",
    "answer": "notochord"
  },
  {
    "question": "What water temperature is preferred for squids?",
    "answer": "Warm"
  },
  {
    "question": "When can you use ready compost?",
    "answer": "After 6 months"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the cephalochordates first appear?",
    "answer": "Cambrian period"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are dolphins born?",
    "answer": "In water"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are the eyes of starfish located?",
    "answer": "At the tips of their arms"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are the lateral line organs located on a shark?",
    "answer": "On the sides"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can you see birds listed in the Red Book?",
    "answer": "Gibbons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can you see nesting flamingos?",
    "answer": "Chelkar-Abaginsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can you see rare grasshoppers?",
    "answer": "Akshinsky Nature Reserve"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where can you see the Eastern Curlew?",
    "answer": "Kuril Islands"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where do echidnas lay their eggs?",
    "answer": "In a pouch"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where do giant squids live?",
    "answer": "In the ocean"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where do rare species of sandpipers inhabit?",
    "answer": "Vitimsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where do tarsiers live?",
    "answer": "Southeast Asia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where do water scorpions live?",
    "answer": "Freshwater bodies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the snow leopard live?",
    "answer": "Sayano-Shushensky Nature Reserve"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is The International tournament usually held?",
    "answer": "DOOM 2016"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the 'Stolby' Nature Reserve located?",
    "answer": "Krasnoyarsk Krai"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the Bastak Nature Reserve located?",
    "answer": "Jewish Autonomous Region"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the Far Eastern Marine Reserve located?",
    "answer": "Primorsky Krai"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the Kronotsky Nature Reserve located?",
    "answer": "Kamchatka"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the nerve cord located in cephalochordates?",
    "answer": "above the notochord"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which MTG set first introduced double-faced cards?",
    "answer": "Innistrad"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Russian nature reserve is famous for its population of brown bears?",
    "answer": "Kronotsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which VR game allows you to control the movements of a pirate ship?",
    "answer": "Sea of Pirates"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which VR game is known for its thrilling tank battles?",
    "answer": "World of Tanks VR"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Yu-Gi-Oh! set introduced the 'Destiny Hero' series of cards?",
    "answer": "Just a Line"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ancestors of modern cephalochordates have an ancient commonality?",
    "answer": "Tunicates"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal belongs to the group of cetaceans and is known for its long white tusks?",
    "answer": "Narwhal"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal can change its color?",
    "answer": "Chameleon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal can eat more than 100 kg of vegetation per day?",
    "answer": "Elephant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal can regenerate its tentacles?",
    "answer": "Squid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal can transmit a radio signal over the longest distance?",
    "answer": "Elephant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal eats branches and roots?",
    "answer": "Beaver"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal eats cacti?",
    "answer": "Spectacled bear"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal eats pine nuts?",
    "answer": "Chipmunk"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal eats tree buds in winter?",
    "answer": "Moose"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal feeds on mosses and lichens?",
    "answer": "Deer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal has thick orange fur?",
    "answer": "Orangutan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal hunts at close range?",
    "answer": "Wolf"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal inhabits marshy areas and loves algae?",
    "answer": "Capybara"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal is a native of the Himalayas?",
    "answer": "yak"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal is known for its ability to weave webs?",
    "answer": "spider"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal is often depicted as a mammal in the pampas?",
    "answer": "Guanaco"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal is protected in the Lazovsky Nature Reserve?",
    "answer": "Human"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal is protected in the Tigirek Nature Reserve?",
    "answer": "Marmot"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal lives deep in the ocean and has a transparent body?",
    "answer": "Actinaria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal lives in the mountains of Eurasia and feeds on grasses?",
    "answer": "Chamois"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animal lives in the mountains?",
    "answer": "Yaks"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animals are morphologically simple?",
    "answer": "lancelets"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animals eat hay?",
    "answer": "Sheep"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animals hibernate in Canada?",
    "answer": "Deer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animals live in saltwater?",
    "answer": "Hagfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animals live in the jungle and are herbivores?",
    "answer": "Elephant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which animals usually have sharp teeth?",
    "answer": "Predators"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which arthropod has the longest legs?",
    "answer": "Stick insect"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which arthropods can fully regenerate limbs?",
    "answer": "Crabs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which beetle is the largest?",
    "answer": "Hercules beetle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird builds large bowers to attract females?",
    "answer": "Bowerbird"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird builds nests on water?",
    "answer": "Swan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird can dive?",
    "answer": "Cormorant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird can fly in stormy conditions?",
    "answer": "Albatross"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird can stay underwater?",
    "answer": "Loon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird has a crest on its head and a hooked beak?",
    "answer": "frigatebird"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird is capable of deep diving?",
    "answer": "Gannet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird is capable of mimicking sounds?",
    "answer": "raven"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird is famous for its intricate nests in trees?",
    "answer": "weaver"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird is famous for its long beak?",
    "answer": "Hummingbird"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird is famous for nesting on cliffs?",
    "answer": "cormorant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird is known for its 'head-down' flight?",
    "answer": "Peregrine Falcon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird is known for its migrations to Vietnam?",
    "answer": "Stork"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird is named after a hero of Greek mythology?",
    "answer": "Phoenix"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird is native only to New Zealand?",
    "answer": "kiwi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird is the loudest?",
    "answer": "Jackdaw"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird lives in the desert?",
    "answer": "ostrich"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bird returns to the north first?",
    "answer": "Rook"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which birds are known for their ability to rapidly change flight altitude?",
    "answer": "Swifts"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which birds are known for their long-distance migrations?",
    "answer": "Cranes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which birds build nests in burrows?",
    "answer": "Kingfishers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which birds build nests out of clay?",
    "answer": "Swallows"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which birds can fly backwards?",
    "answer": "Hummingbirds"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which body part do insects not have?",
    "answer": "Tentacles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which car manufacturer was the first to use a carbon fiber monocoque?",
    "answer": "McLaren"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which car manufacturer was the first to use the double diffuser system?",
    "answer": "Brawn GP"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which creature emits light in the dark?",
    "answer": "Sea firefly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which creature is known for its beautiful iridescent scales and inhabits coral reefs?",
    "answer": "Parrotfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which crocodiles inhabit South America?",
    "answer": "Caimans"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which crustaceans can fully regenerate limbs?",
    "answer": "Lobsters"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which cultivation method is most commonly used in greenhouses?",
    "answer": "Hydroponics"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which echinoderms live on the sea and ocean floors and filter water?",
    "answer": "Crinoids"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which echinoderms resemble lilies?",
    "answer": "Sea lilies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which faction is represented in World of Warcraft?",
    "answer": "Horde"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which female tennis player was the first to retire after winning all Grand Slam tournaments twice?",
    "answer": "Margaret Court"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fertilizers are natural?",
    "answer": "Manure"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which figure skating element requires the most artistry?",
    "answer": "Step sequences"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish are capable of actively hunting?",
    "answer": "Jawed fish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish are capable of breathing air?",
    "answer": "anabas"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish builds nests?",
    "answer": "Stickleback"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish can change its color?",
    "answer": "Platax"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish can change its shape?",
    "answer": "Flounder"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish can fly above the water?",
    "answer": "Flying fish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish can go on land?",
    "answer": "Bichir"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish can reach a length of over 2 meters?",
    "answer": "Eel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish has bioluminescent organs?",
    "answer": "Anglerfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish has rhomboid-shaped scales?",
    "answer": "Gar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish has the ability to quickly change direction?",
    "answer": "Barracuda"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish inhabits coral reefs and has poisonous organs?",
    "answer": "Stonefish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish is called the 'living sea antenna'?",
    "answer": "Batfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish is called the sea wolf?",
    "answer": "European seabass"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish is capable of changing its sex during its lifetime?",
    "answer": "Grouper"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish is capable of regeneration?",
    "answer": "Coelacanth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish is known as a coral predator?",
    "answer": "Parrotfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish is known for having the largest population?",
    "answer": "Tuna"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish is known for its curved body?",
    "answer": "Moray eel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish lives in cold waters?",
    "answer": "Pacific saury"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish lives in the Baltic Sea?",
    "answer": "Herring"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish lives under the ice?",
    "answer": "Antarctic toothfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish produces low-frequency sounds?",
    "answer": "Triggerfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish uses electricity for orientation?",
    "answer": "Knifefish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fish were the ancestors of jawed vertebrates?",
    "answer": "Placoderms"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flower blooms for only one day?",
    "answer": "Hibiscus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flower is known as the 'Queen of the Night'?",
    "answer": "Night-blooming cereus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flower was used to create a natural incubator?",
    "answer": "orchid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flowers come alive at night?",
    "answer": "Moonflowers"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which flowers symbolize eternal love and devotion?",
    "answer": "Tulips"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fly transmits sleeping sickness?",
    "answer": "Tsetse fly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fruit is a symbol of love?",
    "answer": "Pomegranate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fruit is a symbol of the Carthage location?",
    "answer": "Pomegranate"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fruit is called the queen of fruits?",
    "answer": "Mangosteen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fruit is drought-resistant?",
    "answer": "Monophyllia"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which game allows you to recreate historical battles and scenarios?",
    "answer": "Total War"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which game is about investigating a murder involving ghosts?",
    "answer": "Star Trek: Bridge Crew"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which game is based on myths and legends?",
    "answer": "Myth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which game is considered a masterpiece of the Total War series?",
    "answer": "Prey"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which game is considered the first esports discipline?",
    "answer": "Quake"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which game is popular for its dark atmosphere?",
    "answer": "No Man's Sky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which game series is known for its difficulty and rolling mechanics?",
    "answer": "Dark Souls"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which game uses the mechanic of managing ecological balance?",
    "answer": "Terraforming Mars"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which gaming console was the first 16-bit console?",
    "answer": "Sega Genesis"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which garden element is used to create relief?",
    "answer": "Terraces"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which herbivore is the largest antelope?",
    "answer": "Eland"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which herbivorous animal lives high in the mountains?",
    "answer": "Goat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which herbivorous animal most often falls prey to a leopard?",
    "answer": "impala"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect builds burrows?",
    "answer": "cricket"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect has the longest antennae?",
    "answer": "Longhorn beetle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect has the strongest jaws?",
    "answer": "Antlion"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect infects mosquitoes with viruses?",
    "answer": "Nematodes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect is a symbol of bravery in China?",
    "answer": "Dragonfly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect is considered the most venomous?",
    "answer": "Bullet ant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect is often found in fogs?",
    "answer": "Mosquito"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect lives in water?",
    "answer": "Water strider"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect makes an unusual sound when threatened?",
    "answer": "Dung beetle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insect uses mimicry for protection?",
    "answer": "Butterfly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects are beneficial to humans?",
    "answer": "Bees"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects are capable of changing color?",
    "answer": "Chameleon beetles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects feed on carrion?",
    "answer": "Burying beetles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects glow in the dark?",
    "answer": "fireflies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects have soldier castes?",
    "answer": "Termites"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects have spiny legs?",
    "answer": "Colorado beetles"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects hibernate in trees?",
    "answer": "Lacewings"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects migrate long distances?",
    "answer": "butterflies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects often attack berry crops?",
    "answer": "Aphids"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects prefer to feed on dead organic matter?",
    "answer": "Flies"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects secrete saliva to create silky threads?",
    "answer": "Caterpillars"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which insects use pheromones for communication?",
    "answer": "Ants"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which jawed fish can breathe air?",
    "answer": "Lungfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which jellyfish is known for its deadly venom?",
    "answer": "Box jellyfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which large herbivorous animal lives in rivers and lakes?",
    "answer": "hippopotamus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which living creature carries anodes?",
    "answer": "Anodoreya"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which lizard is considered sacred in Egypt?",
    "answer": "Gecko"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which lizard is known for freezing when scared?",
    "answer": "Champion iguana"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal can mimic the human voice?",
    "answer": "Whale"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal gives birth to the largest number of offspring at one time?",
    "answer": "Domestic pig"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal has the longest sleep duration?",
    "answer": "Bat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal has the longest tongue?",
    "answer": "Pangolin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal has the sharpest hearing?",
    "answer": "Bat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal hunts at night?",
    "answer": "Cat"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal hunts seals?",
    "answer": "Orca"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal inhabits high-altitude forests?",
    "answer": "Orangutan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal is a carrier of fungi?",
    "answer": "Several hours"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal is an endangered species from South America?",
    "answer": "Jaguar"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal is capable of changing the color of its fur?",
    "answer": "ermine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal is capable of making fire?",
    "answer": "Human"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal is capable of sleeping up to 20 hours a day?",
    "answer": "Koala"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal is known for its unique vocal apparatus?",
    "answer": "Sperm whale"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal is the smallest in terms of population?",
    "answer": "Vaquita"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal lives in Antarctica?",
    "answer": "Whale"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal migrates the longest distances?",
    "answer": "Whale"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mammal regurgitates its stomach contents when threatened?",
    "answer": "Underground pig"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which marine creature builds trap-nests?",
    "answer": "Dusky jawfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which marine creature has the ability to bioluminesce?",
    "answer": "Sea firefly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which marine creature is often called the 'engineer of the coral reef'?",
    "answer": "Coral polyp"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which marine creature uses its nose to move objects?",
    "answer": "Elephant fish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which method creates an unfavorable environment for pests in the garden?",
    "answer": "Mulching"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which microorganisms are important for neutralizing pathogens?",
    "answer": "Bacteria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which microorganisms are important for soil?",
    "answer": "Nitrogen-fixing bacteria"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mollusk is the most venomous?",
    "answer": "Cone snail"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mollusk listed is the smallest?",
    "answer": "Small slug"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mollusk moves using jet propulsion?",
    "answer": "Squid"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mollusk produces the largest shells in the world?",
    "answer": "Tridacna"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mollusks are capable of photosynthesis?",
    "answer": "Elysia chlorotica"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mollusks are known as dangerous predators?",
    "answer": "Cones"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mollusks often attach themselves to rocks?",
    "answer": "Abalones"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which monkey is carnivorous?",
    "answer": "Chimpanzee"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nature reserve is famous for a large number of orchid species?",
    "answer": "Ladoga"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nature reserve is famous for its ornithological station?",
    "answer": "Prioksko-Terrasny"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nature reserve is famous for rare animals?",
    "answer": "Darvinsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nature reserve is famous for red pandas?",
    "answer": "Kaurymsky Nature Reserve"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nature reserve is known for its diverse grasslands?",
    "answer": "Kuban-Anik"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nature reserve is known for its population of Amur tigers?",
    "answer": "Sikhote-Alin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nature reserve is known for its salt lakes?",
    "answer": "Ashuluksky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nature reserve is known for rare plants in the Altai Krai?",
    "answer": "Katunsky"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nature reserve is known for rare species of rodents?",
    "answer": "Far Eastern Marine Reserve"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nature reserve is located on Wrangel Island?",
    "answer": "Wrangel Island"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nature reserve is located on the Taymyr Peninsula?",
    "answer": "Great Arctic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the animals feed exclusively on leaves?",
    "answer": "Koala"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following animals is the smallest herbivore?",
    "answer": "Mouse"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these primates has the shortest tail?",
    "answer": "Rhesus macaque"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organ do grasshoppers use to produce sounds?",
    "answer": "Wings"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organ helps mollusks to feed?",
    "answer": "radula"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organ in gastropod mollusks contains most of the internal organs?",
    "answer": "Visceral hump"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organs allow hagfish to hide in substrates?",
    "answer": "Slime"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organs are absent in a lancelet?",
    "answer": "Brain"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organs help echinoderms navigate their environment?",
    "answer": "Receptors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organs in echinoderms facilitate the exchange of substances?",
    "answer": "tube feet"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of a fish's skeleton is cartilaginous?",
    "answer": "Gills"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which part of the body of jawless fish is particularly well-developed for regeneration?",
    "answer": "Notochord"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pest control method involves the use of directed light?",
    "answer": "Photoperception"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pest control method is considered organic?",
    "answer": "Using ash"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pest often affects apple trees?",
    "answer": "Codling moth"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pest often attacks eggplants?",
    "answer": "Colorado potato beetle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which physical parameter of a wave determines its potential speed and energy for a surfer?",
    "answer": "Height"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plant leaves should be avoided in compost?",
    "answer": "Coniferous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are best suited for dry areas?",
    "answer": "Succulents"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants are popular for creating a flower bed background?",
    "answer": "Hydrangea"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which plants grow best in the sun?",
    "answer": "Annuals"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primate can swim?",
    "answer": "Macaque"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primate has a high forehead?",
    "answer": "Chimpanzee"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primate has the longest childhood period?",
    "answer": "Chimpanzee"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primate is known for its complex nests?",
    "answer": "orangutan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primate is known for its predatory behavior?",
    "answer": "Baboon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primate is known for its red face?",
    "answer": "uakari"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primate monkey is known for its yellow fur?",
    "answer": "howler monkey"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primate most commonly has white fur?",
    "answer": "Tamarin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primates are capable of gliding from tree to tree?",
    "answer": "Flying lemurs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primates are known for their monogamous mating?",
    "answer": "Gibbons"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primates are often found in high-altitude regions?",
    "answer": "Langurs"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which primates can swim?",
    "answer": "Proboscis monkeys"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which reptile can move its eyes independently of each other?",
    "answer": "Chameleon"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which reptile can walk on water?",
    "answer": "Basilisk"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which reptile has the most powerful bite?",
    "answer": "Crocodile"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which reptile is called the 'queen of the desert'?",
    "answer": "Tuatara"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which reptile is capable of withstanding high temperatures?",
    "answer": "Desert lizard"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which reserve does Mount Elbrus belong to?",
    "answer": "Kabardino-Balkarian"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sea animal is carnivorous?",
    "answer": "Moray eel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sea creature has a ring-shaped body structure?",
    "answer": "Jellyfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sea creature is known for its solitude?",
    "answer": "Moray eel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sea creature is often called a dancer?",
    "answer": "Seahorse"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sea creature uses camouflage?",
    "answer": "Octopus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which seabird is known for its long migrations?",
    "answer": "Albatross"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which senses are developed in cephalochordates?",
    "answer": "Tactile"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which snail is a predator?",
    "answer": "Harpoon snail"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which snail is considered dangerous to humans?",
    "answer": "Cone snail"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which snail is known as a plant pest?",
    "answer": "slug"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which snail produces venom?",
    "answer": "Cone snail"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which snake can breathe through its skin?",
    "answer": "Garter"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which snake is considered the most venomous?",
    "answer": "Inland Taipan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which snake is known for its beautiful skin patterns?",
    "answer": "King Cobra"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which snake lives in trees?",
    "answer": "Green mamba"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which snakes are capable of gliding?",
    "answer": "Flying snakes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which snowboard parameter affects its performance in deep snow?",
    "answer": "Nose width"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which system in echinoderms is involved in nutrition?",
    "answer": "Digestive"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which system is absent in cephalochordates?",
    "answer": "closed circulatory"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which system is the most developed in lampreys?",
    "answer": "Nervous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which technique helps improve soil?",
    "answer": "Vermicomposting"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which technique involves the use of water elements?",
    "answer": "Hydroponics"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tennis player was the first to retire after winning over 1000 doubles matches?",
    "answer": "Daniel Nestor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tick is commonly found on animals?",
    "answer": "Ixodid tick"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which turtle can breathe through its skin?",
    "answer": "Radiated tortoise"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of fish is known for its unique way of catching prey using a glowing lure?",
    "answer": "Anglerfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of whale can reach speeds of up to 56 km/h?",
    "answer": "Fin whale"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which vegetable is often grown on circular beds?",
    "answer": "Pumpkin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which vegetables prefer acidic soil?",
    "answer": "Potatoes"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which vegetables prefer shade?",
    "answer": "Spinach"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which whale can hold its breath for up to 90 minutes?",
    "answer": "sperm whale"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which whale makes a 'rumble' sound?",
    "answer": "Sperm whale"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which whales use echolocation?",
    "answer": "Toothed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who became the symbol of Formula 1 in the 1970s?",
    "answer": "James Hunt"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who builds \"complex nests\" in trees?",
    "answer": "Penduline tit"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created Metal Gear Solid?",
    "answer": "Hideo Kojima"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is a well-known enemy of the clownfish?",
    "answer": "Sea snake"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is known as the 'king of the skies'?",
    "answer": "Eagle"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the main antagonist in the game Hyper Light Drifter?",
    "answer": "Titans"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the main character in the game Dead Cells?",
    "answer": "The Prisoner"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the main predator of corals?",
    "answer": "Crown-of-thorns starfish"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first female world champion?",
    "answer": "Malvina Kremer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first rider to win Paris-Roubaix in rainy weather?",
    "answer": "Francesco Moser"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first to jump over 2.45 meters in high jump?",
    "answer": "Javier Sotomayor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first to set a record on the climb to Alpe d'Huez?",
    "answer": "Pierre Rolland"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first to study arthropods under a microscope?",
    "answer": "Antonie van Leeuwenhoek"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the top scorer in Serie A for the 2020/2021 season?",
    "answer": "Cristiano Ronaldo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who were the ancient ancestors of lancelets?",
    "answer": "Tunicates"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the MPL tournament in 2020?",
    "answer": "Bren Esports"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whose remains are considered the first jawed vertebrates?",
    "answer": "Placoderms"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do sea cucumbers wash up on shore?",
    "answer": "Defensive reaction"
  }
]